♪〜
〜♪
（小鳥のさえずり）
（ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード）
はああ〜
おはよう 小鳥さん
Good morning, birdies.
My name is
Vash the Stampede.
（ヴァッシュ）私の名は
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード
I have been a hunter of peace
who chases the mayfly known as love...
愛という かげろうを追い続ける
平和の狩人を続けて 早幾とせ
...for many, many moons now.
平和を求める私に安息はない
There is no rest for me
in my search for peace.
I meditate diligently
every morning.
欠かさぬ朝のめい想
テーマは「人生と愛」
The subjects are life and love.
３秒でやめる
I quit after 3 seconds.
平和を求める私は
トレーニングも欠かさない
In my search for peace,
I also train diligently.
（ヴァッシュ）あっ
（卵が割れる音）
Thanks, friend.
And, farewell.
（ヴァッシュ）
ありがとう 友よ… さらばだ
Hey, Vash!
（子どもＡ）ヴァッシュ！
早くしろよ 行こうぜ
Hurry up, would you?
Let's go!
（ヴァッシュ）おう！
Right!
（ヴァッシュ）
未来を担う子どもたちに—
It is also my mission to teach
the precious value of peace...
平和の尊さを教えるのも
私の使命である
...to the children who will
one day own the world.
（関節が鳴る音）
（ヴァッシュ）
あーっ 痛い 痛い 痛い
Ow, ow, ow!
Hey, ma'am. Mr. Vash is being put in
strangleholds by the children again.
（ミリィ･トンプソン）
先輩 またヴァッシュさんが
子どもたちに関節くらってますよ
That's nice.
（メリル･ストライフ）あっそ…
I will say it again:
（ヴァッシュ）
もう一度 言おう
My name is Vash the Stampede.
私の名は
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード
Hey, quit moving around!
I am a hunter of peace
who chases the mayfly known as love.
愛という かげろうを
追い続ける平和の狩人だ
（ミシェル）あ？
ああっ
だ… 大丈夫ですか？
A-Are you okay?
Aileen?!
アイリーン！
はっ？
I'm sorry, it's just that you look
so much like my girlfriend who died...
いえ あなたが死んだ恋人と
うり二つだったものですから
Please tell me your name.
あの… お名前は？
ミ… ミシェルですけど
l-I'm Michelle.
That's a lovely name.
いい名だ
僕の名は
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード
My name is
Vash the Stampede.
That sounds like the name of an outlaw
with $ $60,000,000,000 on his head.
（ミシェル）600億の
賞金首みたいな お名前ですわね
I hear that a lot.
よく言われます
So, what would you say
to having lunch with me?
（ヴァッシュ）…で どうですか？
これから僕と食事にでも
Not a chance.
行きません
That makes 10 misses out of 10.
（子どもＢ）これで10戦10敗か
（子どもＡ）お前のために
やってやったのに
We're doing it for you, you know!
Try a little harder!
（子どもＢ）
もうちょっと頑張れよ
But, Captain, I believe this
strategy is far too difficult!
（ヴァッシュ）隊長 この作戦には
無理がありすぎると思います
Hey, it's Neil!
あっ ニールだ！
Hey, Neil! Wanna join in?
（ヴァッシュ）
よお！ ニール 混ざんねえか？
He's been a real loner lately.
最近 あいつ
つきあい悪(わり)いよなあ
We keep asking him,
but he never comes.
誘っても来ねえしよお
（足音）
あ？
（メリル）ヴァッシュさん
Mr. Vash!
How long do you think this
self-indulgent lifestyle...
何もしないで
子どもと遊んでばっかり
...of doing nothing but
playing with children...
労働もしないで 食べて
寝るだけの じだらくな生活を
...and eating and sleeping without
doing any work whatsoever can last?!
いつまで続けられると
思ってますの？
（子どもＡ）くう… ヤダ ヤダ
Ew, a lecture.
何も言い返せないなんて
だっせえの
Only a wimp would
take that kind of abuse!
Thank you!
（ニール）ありがとうございました
あ…
- Come on.
- Wait, Dad!
（父）さあ おいで
（子）ああ 待ってよ 父さん
ハハハハハッ
アハハハハッ
Neil!
（ヴァッシュ）ニール！
（ニール）あ…
よお！
Hi.
Oh, it's just Vash.
なんだ ヴァッシュか…
That's not a very warm hello.
（ヴァッシュ）
“なんだ”とは ご挨拶だなあ
Hey, good for you!
Are you helping out?
偉いじゃん 店の手伝いか？
That's none of your business.
関係ねえだろ
Don't be so cross.
そうツンケンすんなよ
お前んち 食堂だったろ？
Hey, doesn't your family
run a restaurant?
I'm starved. Could you
give me something to eat?
腹減ってんだ
何か食わしてくんねえか
You're not getting any handouts.
タダメシは ごめんだぞ
I know that.
（ヴァッシュ）分かってますって
And keep your hands off my mom.
母ちゃんに手え出すなよ
どういう意味？
Meaning?
母ちゃん！ お客
Mom, a customer!
Welcome!
（クレア）いらっしゃいませ
Wow!
わーおっ
（ニコラス･Ｄ･ウルフウッド）
イヒヒヒッ
Come on in!
毎度！
Don't wreck the place, stupid!
（ニール）店 壊すなよ バカ
And what are you doing here?
何をしてんのかな？ 君は
Can't you tell?
I'm helping out.
（ウルフウッド）見たら分かるやろ
手伝いに決まっとるがな
And why is that?
（ヴァッシュ）どうして？
It's only natural
to help those in need.
（ウルフウッド）困ってる人を
助けるのは当たり前やろが
Here you go! All done!
はいよ！ できたで
I'm sorry. I'm
asking so much of you...
すみません こんなことまで
させてしまって…
Think nothing of it.
I'm doing it because I want to.
かまへんて こっちは
好きでやらしてもろとるんや
Take it before it gets cold.
冷める前に早よ持ってき
All right.
（クレア）はい
Here you are!
お待たせしました
Did something happen?
何かあったのか？
ぐっ…
Thank Heaven you asked!
よう聞いてくれた！
It's a long story,
although it's kind of short.
話せば長いようで
短いんやけどな
Anyways, it's like this:
つまり こういうこっちゃ
Just when I happened
to stop by here to eat...
（ウルフウッド）たまたまこの店で
メシ食おう思て来たときにな
（クレア）キャーッ
What're you doing to my mom?!
（ニール）母ちゃんに何すんだ！
Please! I'll pay you the money,
so just wait a little longer, please!!
お願いします
お金は必ず払いますから—
もう少しだけ待ってください
Lady, you're long
past your deadline.
奥さん 期限は
とっくに過ぎてんだよ
Unless you pay off your debt in full,
we can't make any money either.
耳そろえて払ってもらわねえと
こっちの商売も上がったりでなあ
ケケケッ
So, things being
as they were...
まっ そないなこと
しとったんで—
...I talked them out of it
with a little of His gospel.
ちょこっと神の説法を
説いたったわけや
Once I asked the lady...
奥さんに聞いたらな
...she says that her husband went
missing, leaving his debt behind.
旦那が借金こさえて おらんように
なったっちゅうやんか
But for all that,
she keeps the place running.
それでも頑張って店続けとる
Even the little boy is desperate
to help his mother.
子どもも そないな母親の
手伝いしようと必死や
It shot me through the heart.
胸打たれたわあ
Could you just sit there?
Could you just ignore that?!
黙っとられへんやろ
ほっとかれへんやろ？
So that's how it was!
そういうことか…
That's how it was.
そういうことや
（ヴァッシュ）悲しい話だな おい
That's so sad!
Isn't it?
Don't you think so?
そうやろ？ そう思うやろ
I think so!
I think incredibly so!
思う… 猛烈に思うよ 僕は！
しかし 手間省けたわ
But now, you saved
me some trouble.
I was gonna go look for you
once we closed shop.
店はけたら捜しに行こう思とってん
- For me?
- Yup.
（ヴァッシュ）俺を？
（ウルフウッド）そや
“第３回クイックドロウ大会
賞金５万ダブドル…” 何これ？
The 3rd Annual
Quick Draw Tournament...
...Grand Prize: $ $50,000?
Whassis?
You're going to compete
to help out a poor family.
不幸な親子のために
あんたが出るんや
はあ？
That's right. All you have to do
is show up there tomorrow.
ああ あしたは身１つで
会場に来たらええで
I'll take care of the
registration for you.
登録は わいが
済ませとくさかいにな
Why me, all of a sudden?!
何でそうなんのよ
We're helping people here!
人助けせえっちゅうとんのや
Or would you rather
I turned you in...
それとも何か？ あんた
役所につき出して
...and collect the
$ $60,000,000,000 instead?
600億ダブドルもろても
ええんか？
That's not funny, pal.
それは困るよ 君…
Just look at her.
見てみい
Isn't that a sad face?
悲しそうな横顔やろ？
Yeah.
（ヴァッシュ）ああ
（ウルフウッド）器量もええで
Isn't that a beautiful face?
Yeah!
- For love!
- And peace!
（ヴァッシュ）愛と
（ウルフウッド）平和のために
A quick draw tournament?!
（メリル）クイックドロウ大会？
ああ
Yeah!
What is going on
in your head?
何を考えてるんですの？ あなたは
Even an idiot could foresee the danger
of your participation in such a contest.
そんな大会に出たら どうなるか
考えれば分かりますわよ 普通
うーん どうも のせられちゃって
そうなっちゃたんだよねえ
I was kind of talked into it...
...and now I'm in the contest.
By whom?
（メリル）誰に？
The priest we met on the bus!
バスで会った牧師さん
Hey, Mr. Vash! Once you win the prize,
treat me to something, okay?
ヴァッシュさん 賞金出たら
おごってくださいね
I'll think about it.
（ヴァッシュ）アハッ 考えとく
I'm having visions!
I'm having unhappy visions!
ああっ 見える！
不幸なビジョンが見えてきますわ
Dozens of show-off gunmen
after the $ $60,000,000,000...
（メリル）腕自慢のガンマンが
600億ダブドルの賞金目当てに—
...are already shooting up
the town inside of my head!
銃撃戦を繰り広げる光景が…
I'm just taking part in a fun
contest, that's all. It's okay!
（ヴァッシュ）
お遊びの大会に出るだけさ
大丈夫だって
You're completely
illogical, aren't you?
根拠がまったくありませんね
You like to speak
your mind, don't you?
（ヴァッシュ）
ひと言 多いね 君は
My boss told me
the exact same thing!
部長にも言われました
It'll be okay, all right?
（ヴァッシュ）
大丈夫だって 大丈夫…
It'll be okay...
うーん…
...probably.
たぶんね
Sir, when we were going through
today's entries, this name came up.
（執事）旦那様　今日
出場登録をしてきた者の中に—
こんな名前が…
Vash the Stampede?
（主催者）
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピード？
This is a troubling
turn of events.
（執事）大変なことになりました
出場を取り消しますか？
Shall I have his
entry withdrawn?
I highly doubt the legendary
gunman would come out of hiding...
（主催者）伝説のガンマンが—
たかが５万ダブドルの賞金のために
出場してくるとは思えんな
...for a mere $ $50,000 prize.
It's just a punk
using the name for kicks.
名前を語ってるだけの
ただのチンピラだ
But, sir!
しかし…
If we let him try, we'll soon
know whether he's the real thing.
本物かどうかは
やらせてみればすぐに分かるさ
We will hold the tournament
as planned.
大会は予定どおり開催する
That is all. Go!
（主催者）もういい 下がれ
（執事）かしこまりました
Understood.
（ドアの開閉音）
Will this do?
（主催者）
これで… よろしいのですか？
（ノックする音）
（ヴァッシュ）誰さん？
Who is it?
It's me!
（ウルフウッド）わいや
（ヴァッシュ）鍵は開いてるよ
It's open.
Hey! You still up?
よおっ 起きとったか？
The lady gave us a present!
Care for a glass?
奥さんが差し入れしてくれてな
どや？ １杯
（ウルフウッド）悪かったなあ
無理やり巻き込んでしもて
Sorry about all this...
I didn't mean to
force you into it.
計算ずくだったくせに
You planned it
from the start!
Well, yeah,
but I apologized, didn't I?
（ウルフウッド）
そやから 悪かったて
（ヴァッシュ）教会…
A church...
ん？
教会から来たって言ったろ
どこにあるんだ？
You said you came from
a church. Where is it?
（ウルフウッド）ディセムバから
300アイル離れたとこや
It's 300 iles from December.
You take orphans
that far away?
そんな田舎に孤児を集めてんのか？
I can't help but
bring them there...
連れてきてしまうんや
旅先で会うた 親 殺されとったり
捨てられとったりしたガキどもをな
...kids I run into who have had
their parents killed, abandoned kids...
そやけど あの
ニールっちゅうガキは—
But I don't want
to take that Neil kid.
連れていきとうないねん
また笑ろたな ええ顔や
There's that smile again.
It suits you.
Hey, girls!
おねえちゃんたち！
（ミリィ）あっ
（メリル）うう…
（ウルフウッド）
そんなとこにおらんで入ってきいな
Don't hang around there,
come on in!
（ミリィ）エヘへへへ
I apologize for eavesdropping...
盗み聞きしたことは謝りますわ
でも これで 大体の
事情が飲み込めました
...but now I have a basic
grasp of the situation.
（メリル）ヴァッシュさん
（ヴァッシュ）はい
- Mr. Vash?
- Yes?
I'll turn a blind eye
once again.
今回も目をつぶってさしあげますわ
ですから がっ がが…
So, g...
G, g, g...
Give 'em heck, Mr. Vash!
頑張ってくださいね
ヴァッシュさん
ありがと
- Thanks.
- So, who's up for a drink?
さっ 飲もうや
はーい はーい はーい
Me, me, me!
Uh, don't let her
have too much!
ああっ その子には
あまり飲ませちゃ…
（ウルフウッド）
固いこと言うなって
Hey, lighten up!
（ミリィ）先輩 私 暑い…
Ma'am... I feel so hot!
Hey, don't do that here!
（メリル）
およしなさい こんな所で…
You go, big girl!
（ウルフウッド）
ええぞ 大きいねえちゃん
（ミリィ）これもいらなーい
（ヴァッシュ）うわっ ああ…
（ウルフウッド）ありえへんが…
Whoa...
（発砲音）
Whoa. We got in some
amazing gunmen this year.
（客Ａ）おいおい 今年も
すげえガンマンが集まってきたぞ
（客Ｂ）おお 何だ
あの銃は ワクワクするぜ
Get a load of that gun!
This'll be great!
Mr. Vash and Wolfwood
haven't arrived yet.
（ミリィ）ヴァッシュさんたち
まだ来てませんね
Well, you saw how they were.
They'll come in their own sweet time.
まあ あんな状態でしたからね
ゆっくり来ますわよ
それに ヘタに騒ぎにならなくて
いいかもしれませんわ
Besides, it's probably better if
they don't draw too much attention.
So, shall we go?
（ウルフウッド）さっ 行こか
Please keep your voice down.
It hurts my head.
あんまり大きな声
出さないでくれ 頭に響く
だらしないやっちゃな
あのくらいの酒で
What a slob!
Can't you handle a few drinks?
（ヴァッシュ）僕にとっちゃ
“あのくらい”じゃなくて—
To me, that's not a few drinks,
that's a few freaking dallons!
“あんなにも”なの
そらあ すまなんだ
To each his own.
Vash!
（ニール）ヴァッシュ！
（ヴァッシュ）おお
Hey there!
Are you really
gonna help Mom?!
ホントに母ちゃん
助けてくれんのか？
（クレア）よしなさい ニール
Stop that, Neil.
I can't have you, a total
stranger, do this for me!
見ず知らずのあなたに
ここまでしてもらうわけには…
もう知り合いですよ それに
こういうの結構 得意なんですよ
We're acquaintances now!
And besides, I'm pretty good
at this sort of thing, actually.
実は… アッハハハハ
（銃声）
（観客のざわめき）
（客Ａ）なんだよ
１発も当たんねえじゃねえか
What was that?
He can't hit a single one.
Damn!
（ガンマンＡ）クソッ
（銃声）
ヴァッシュが出てるって？
Vash is in the tournament?!
You think he's any good?
大丈夫なのかよ あいつで
There he is, over there!
（子どもＢ）
あっ いたいた あそこ
（ヴァッシュ）ヒッ うう…
He's a lost cause.
（子どもＡ）ダメっぽいなあ
（ヴァッシュ）ううっ う…
（銃声）
す… すげえ！
Holy crap!
あいつが そうか…
やるじゃないか
Is that the guy?
He's not bad!
Oops...
I hit 'em all.
（ヴァッシュ）しまった…
全部 当たっちゃったよ
ハアア…
You're Vash the Stampede
all right.
（ウルフウッド）さすがは
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードや
（ヴァッシュ）目立ちすぎだよ
I'm standing out too much.
勝負がやりやすくなって
ええやんか
It'll make the going easier.
Keep knocking 'em dead.
この調子で きばってや
That goes for you, too.
（ヴァッシュ）君もね
なんやて？
Say what?
Is the 3rd round contestant,
Nicholas D. Wolfwood, present?
（係員）第３回戦の出場者
ニコラス･Ｄ･ウルフウッドさんは
いませんか？
このままでは失格になります
Step forward now,
or be disqualified!
What the hell did
you sign me up for?!
おのれ 勝手に何してくれんねん！
If we both compete, it'll
boost the chances of winning.
２人で出たほうが勝率上がるでしょ
何い！
What?!
Good luck, Mr. Priest Man!
頑張れ 牧師のあんちゃん！
Aw, man...
あっちゃーっ
あ？
- For love...
- And peace.
（ヴァッシュ）愛と
（ウルフウッド）平和のために
（銃声）
（歓声）
（ウルフウッド）フンッ
That was so amazing!
すごい すごーい！ どうして
そんなに上手なんですか？
How come you're
so good at that?
We live in a dangerous world.
It's for self-protection.
世の中 物騒なこと多いやんか
自衛のためや
Maybe you're an ex-gunman!
元ガンマンだったりして
Get real!
そんなことあるかあ
- What're you lookin' at?
- Nothin'.
（ウルフウッド）なんや？
（ヴァッシュ）別に
You guys are pretty good.
（ガンマンＢ）
やるじゃねえか 兄ちゃんたちよお
But this is the end
of your spree.
だが その活躍もここまでだ
You're not against no
liquor bottles this time.
これからは酒瓶相手の
腕試しじゃねえ
This time, it's live
one-on-one combat.
１対１のリアルファイトだ
（ヴァッシュ）ええ！
（ウルフウッド）知らんかったんか
You didn't know?!
（発砲音）
（ガンマンＣ）フッフフフ…
ここでやめていい？
Can I drop out now?
お前 人 巻き込んどいて
んなこと言うか！
You dragged me into this,
so bite your tongue!
（ガンマンたちの荒い息遣い）
（銃声）
うう…
（医者）ハーッハハ
命拾いしたな 肩の傷だけじゃ
You're very lucky!
It's just your shoulder.
You're good at knocking
bullets off target.
ウマいこと弾道そらすなあ
殺し合いは見たないか？
Don't you want to watch
people kill each other?
- It's your fault I'm here.
- There's no need to thank me.
君が引き込んだからでしょ
気い遣(つこ)とるんやな
We will now commence
the first quarterfinal match!
（係員）準々決勝
第一試合を始めます
It's you and me,
spineless coward.
（ガンマンＢ）
来やがったな 軟弱野郎
Please go easy on me.
お手柔らかに頼みますよ
Ready, go!
（係員）レディー ゴー！
（３人）あっ
あっ
（銃声）
（ヴァッシュ）キャー
（ガンマンＢ）ぐわっ
ヘヘッ やるじゃねえか
Not bad!
I lost, fair...
俺の…
...and square!
負け… だ…
（メリル）前後 逆だったわけ？
（ウルフウッド）せこっ
He was facing backwards
the entire time?!
Cheap!
（発砲音）
（銃声）
フゥーッ
あー イテテテテッ
Ow, ow, ow!
（銃声）
（ガンマンたちのうめき声）
But I shot him first!
This is unusual!
珍しいな 今年はここまでやって
１人も死人がでないとは
So far, we haven't had
a single fatality this year!
ホンモンだ やつはホンモンの
ヴァッシュ･ザ･スタンピードだ
He's the real thing!
He's the real Vash the Stampede!
You're incredible, Vash!
（子どもＡ）すげえよ ヴァッシュ
You have what it takes
to be our underling!
（子どもＢ）
さすが俺たちの下っ端だぜ
Mr. Wolfwood said he was going
to withdraw from the competition...
ウルフウッドさんは出場を
辞退すると言ってましたから
...so now you've won!
これで あなたが優勝ですわ
It went very well!
万事めでたしですね
I'm Nicholas D. Wolfwood.
（ウルフウッド）
ニコラス･Ｄ･ウルフウッドや
I'm withdrawing
from the final round.
決勝は棄権させてもらうで
（主催者）ほう… あれほどの腕を
披露しておきながら なぜかね？
Really? But you were doing
so well for yourself.
Might I ask why?
It's too much of a bother, that's all.
Give the prize to the other guy.
（ウルフウッド）
面倒になっただけや
優勝は もう１人の男にやってくれ
I can't do that.
そうは いかんな
What?
なんやて？
ふーん… そういうことかい
So that's how it is.
Nicholas, you really
are very good.
（主催者）ニコラス君
君は実にいい腕をしている
Would you eliminate Vash the Stampede
with your superb gunmanship for me?
その銃裁きでヴァッシュ･ザ･
スタンピードを消してくれないか
If you do as I say,
I'll guarantee the family's safety...
言うことを聞いてくれれば
あの親子の安全は保証するし—
...and I would even be willing to
raise the prize to $ $30,000,000,000.
優勝賞金を一気に
300億ダブドルにまで—
引き上げてもいい
山分けっちゅうことやな
You mean 50/50?
（主催者）フン…
切れる男は嫌いではないよ
I like a man with
a head on his shoulders.
The final round will now begin!
（係員）これより決勝戦を始めます
（ミリィ）ああ…
（メリル）なんで？
But why?!
Vash...
ヴァッシュ…
Didn't you withdraw?
棄権したんじゃないのか？
Here's the big question:
さて 問題や
What do you see in the window
of that building over there?
あっちの建物の窓には
何が見えとる？
あっ…
And that just about
sums it up.
つまり… そういうこっちゃ
Ready, go!
レディ ゴー！
（銃声）
（ニール）ヴァッシュ！
Vash!
It's for the good of that family!
Quit squirming and die!
あの親子のためや
黙って死んでくれ！
（銃声）
Get serious!
無茶言うな！
I'm saying we all have
to make a few sacrifices!
多少の犠牲は
しゃあないっちゅうとんねん
And I'm one of the few?
（ヴァッシュ）僕は少ないほう？
（銃声）
いっ…
Now ya done it!
やりよったな！
（ヴァッシュ）昨日あんだけ
飲ましたのは このためかい
So this is what you got me
so plastered for yesterday!
（銃声）
You think I'd try
something that cheap?!
（ウルフウッド）わいが そんな
ひきょうなマネする思うとんのんか
（銃声）
（ヴァッシュ）思うよ
勝手に登録したくせに
Yeah, I do, after you went
and signed me up without asking!
（銃声）
You did the same to me!
（ウルフウッド）
おのれも同じやろが
（銃声）
フンッ
（メリルとミリィ）あっ
（ニールとクレア）ああっ
グハハハハッ これで
600億ダブドルは私のものだ
Now the $ $60,000,000,000
are all mine!
Finish them!
とどめをさせ！
（メリルとミリィ）ああっ
（銃声）
（ガンマンたち）ええっ
（ガンマンたち）ヒイイッ
（ウルフウッド）へへへヘヘッ
（銃声）
なにっ！
What?!
（ミリィ）わあっ
K-Kill them!
や… やつらを殺せ！
（複数の銃声）
ねえちゃんたち！
わいの荷物頼むわ
Hey, girls!
Pass me my luggage!
（メリル）えっ？
But it's so big!
（メリル）こんな大きな物…
（ミリィ）こうしましょう！
Let's do this!
（銃をかまえる音）
（メリル）えっ
Step aside, ma'am!
先輩 どいてください
（発砲音）
（ウルフウッド）おおきに！
（ヴァッシュ）おい 殺すなよ
Thanks!
Hey, don't kill them!
（発砲音）
（ヴァッシュ）ああ！
Is this anytime
to be picky?!
この状況で よう言うわ
“なんじ殺すなかれ”
じゃないのかよ
Whatever happened to
"Thou shalt not kill"?!
（銃声）
（ウルフウッド）おりゃあ！
（ガンマンたち）うわあっ
どりゃあ！
（続く銃声）
これ以上 増やさへん 絶対に…
I won't let any
more children suffer!
Never again!
NEVERAGAI N!
絶対に！
（ガンマンたちのうめき声）
（医者）ああ こりゃ大変じゃ
This is horrible.
どうすんのよ こんなにケガ人
増やしちゃって まったく…
Why'd you have to go and
injure so many people?
なんて聖職者だよ
What kind of a
churchman are you?
Nobody's dead.
I kept my word.
１人も死んどらん 約束は守ったで
Now then...
さてと…
...may God have mercy
on your soul.
あなたに神の慈悲が
ありますように
Or should I change that to
"May I collect the prize?"
そんでもって わいに
賞金がもらえますように
A-All right...
I'll pay it!
わ… 分かった 払う… 払う！
Much obliged!
おおきに
（子どもＡ）ほれ！
あーっ 痛い 痛い！
ちょっと勘弁してくれ おい
Ow, ow, ow!
Hey, stop it! Hey!
Ah, no! It hurts!!
あかん！ 痛いがなあ
He's become really popular!
すっかり人気者に
なっちゃいましたね
I knew he was
no ordinary priest...
ただの牧師じゃないとは
思ってましたけど
...but I never imagined...
まさか ここまでとは…
（ウルフウッド）
ふぐぐぐぐっ あががーっ
ほい 上がり！
There you go!
ありがとうございます
Thank you so much!
いえいえ なんのなんの
Think nothing of it!
（駆け寄る足音）
（ニール）かかかかか…
M-M-M...
（クレア）どうしたの？ ニール
What's wrong, Neil?
It's d-d-d...
とととと…
（ニール）父ちゃん！
（クレア）あなた…
- Dad!
- Dear!
I'm out of a job.
お役御免だ
Looks that way.
そうみたいやな
- For love...
...and peace.
（ウルフウッド）愛と
（ヴァッシュ）平和のために
（２人）え？
（子どもたち）へへへヘヘッ
（子どもたち）ほれっ
（ウルフウッド）おおーっ
Get 'em!
（ヴァッシュ）
た… 隊長殿！ その技だけは
No, Captain!
Anything but that!!
（関節が鳴る音）
（ヴァッシュ）ノーッ！
（黒猫の鳴き声）
♪〜
〜♪
A choice between two things.
（ヴァッシュ）二者択一
命を与えられた人間が
生き続ける中で—
The forked road every person brought
into the world must eventually face.
避けては通れない分かれ道
それが岐路だ
A crossroad.
どちらに進んでも何かを失う
Whichever path they choose,
they lose something.
どちらに進んでも幸福を
見つけることができない
Whichever path they choose,
they are unable to find happiness.
だが 分かれた道は
本当に２つしかないのか
But are there really only
two paths to a forked road?
No. There are infinite
paths we should take.
違う 進むべき道は
無数にあるはずだ
There is more than one
path we should take.
俺たちの選ぶべき道は
一つじゃない
There is more than
one path to the future.
未来への未知は
決して１つじゃない